You are who you eat.
Ravenous is a adventure, western, horror film directed by Antonia Bird.
Upon receiving reports of missing persons at Fort Spencer, a
remote Army outpost on the Western frontier, Capt.
John Boyd investigates.
After arriving at his new post, Boyd and his regiment aid a wounded frontiersman who recounts a
horrifying tale of a wagon train murdered by its supposed guide – a vicious U.S.
Army colonel gone rogue.
Fearing the worst, the regiment heads out into the
wilderness to verify the gruesome claims.
Boyd, played by Guy Pearce.
Ives / Colqhoun, played by Robert Carlyle.
Cleaves, played by David Arquette.
Toffler, played by Jeremy Davies.
Hart, played by Jeffrey Jones.
General Slauson, played by John Spencer.
Ravenous is a 1999 horror Western film directed by Antonia Bird and starring
Guy Pearce, Robert Carlyle, Jeffrey Jones, and David Arquette.
Set in the 1840s in California's Sierra Nevada, the film follows a group of
soldiers at a military outpost who encounter a sadistic cannibal.
Screenwriter Ted Griffin's screenplay combines elements from the Donner Party and that of Alfred Packer, the real-life "Colorado
Cannibal" who survived by eating five companions after becoming snowbound in the San Juan Mountains in the 1870s.
However, the film's plot also serves as an overt criticism of
manifest destiny through its use of cannibalism.
By turning the act into an insatiable hunger, the voracious need to eat human flesh is equated to the all-consuming pursuit of power and
wealth that was inherent to the expansionist attitudes of those seeking to settle the American frontier in the 19th century.
The film would be the last theatrical release to feature John Spencer.
An international co-production between United Kingdom, United States
and Mexico, Ravenous had a troubled production history.
Issues over budget and shooting schedules were still ongoing
when filming was about to start in Slovakia.
After the original director Milcho Manchevski was fired three weeks into production, he was replaced by Bird at the
suggestion of actor Robert Carlyle who had previously worked with her in 1997 in the movie Face.
The film was shot in Europe and Mexico.
Michael Nyman and Damon Albarn composed the film's score, which generated a significant amount of
interest for its quirky and inventive use of loops, instruments and musical structure.
Released by 20th Century Fox in the spring of 1999, Ravenous was a
box-office bomb, grossing $2 million against a $12 million budget.
However, despite initial reception being mixed when released, it
has since garnered a reputation as a cult film.
The film explores themes of california, army, chase, fort, winter.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.